♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we've got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we'll reset it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko stronger after all ♪
(PHONE RINGING)
Ah-huh?
Yumi? It’s Jeremie.
We need you to come to the
factory right now!
The superscan has just picked up
an attack from Xana.
And this one looks like big trouble.
Why?
Because believe it or not,
there are five activated towers.
I’ve got a bad feeling about this one.
No, Relax Einstein,
we’ll take out your five towers in no time.
I got here as quickly as I could.
Huh?
Ah, there you are.
I’ve been expecting you.
That Xana locks the door,
but leaves the window wide open.
Bu- but I mean,
wh- what are you doing here?
I’m deactivating the towers.
Without going to Lyoko?
Of course.
But-ah, who are you?
What? Haven’t you understood yet?
I’m Franz Hopper.
Huh?
I’m the one who created Lyoko,
and Xana too.
But then I lost control of it.
In the very beginning it was a program--
--that I designed to counter a military project--
--based on a multi-agent system.
Well, what about me?
Eh?
I created you to be the guardian of Lyoko.
But I never thought I’d see you
one day in flesh and blood.
But then, where have you
been for these last few years.
Well let’s say I was kind of prisoner,
who finally managed to escape.
What now then?
We’ve got to destroy Xana
for once and for all.
We’d love to,
but Xana’s given Aelita a bug.
If we switch the supercomputer off,
then Aelita switches off too.
We’ll find the anti-virus. You’ll see.
Sure, but how?
Well, that young man is why I came.
I’m here to help.
He’s very fatherly,
actually in a way he is my father.
He’s the one who created me.
That’s true.
I adore my own dad,
but he’s sure no genius.
But this Franz Hopper is a real live genious.
Yeah, that’s it for me.
I’m gonna go to bed.
Okay, good night.
Good night Jeremie.
(PHONE RINGING)
Jeremie? It’s me.
Franz?
No, Michael. Your father.
Do you know why I’m calling?
Happy birthday big guy.
Huh?
HAPPY BIRTHDAY EINSTEIN!
By the way,
your mother’s worried about you.
You should call us more often.
Now, have you thought about
that school for gifted children?
Jeremie?
Uh, yeah sure.
Ok dad, sure.
Uh, listen I have to go.
My friends just came in.
Talk to you soon!
Here, a present.
What are you waiting for,
go on, open it!
Wow! It’s great!
Yeah! And I drew it from memory!
So you can imagine
how much effort it took.
(LAUGHTER)
Thanks everyone!
Hey, how about going over
to the factory now?
I can’t wait to see Franz again.
You used the scanners to
virtualize human beings?
Well, yes.
It’s the only way we could
find to deactivate towers on Lyoko.
The virtualization process
was not ready for that yet.
It’s a very dangerous procedure,
with serious side effects.
Such as?
Cell degeneration.
Odd seems ok.
Ulrich too.
But Yumi…
No! It can’t be!
I can’t believe it!
What a nightmare.
Nice one Einstein.
Dr. Shrank transplants animal limbs onto human beings,
but compared to you he’s small time.
I… I couldn’t have known.
I’m sorry.
You’re sorry?
Well that’s not gonna help cure Yumi.
Yumi, I…
Leave me alone Jeremie…
I need to be by myself.
You coming Ulrich?
I’m sure there is
a way to cure Yumi.
We don’t even know
exactly what’s wrong with her.
I’ll work it out.
I promise I will.
I think you’ve done
enough damage as it is.
What do you mean by that?!
That everything’s been my
fault right from the start?!
You’re the brains in this
outfit, Einstein.
You know Ulrich, if it weren’t for the scanners,
I wouldn’t be here.
Yumi?
Are you okay?
I’m not very hungry tonight.
(LAUGHTER)
Oh Ulrich, I love you.
Hiroki!
I’m going to bed.
That’s it then.
We’re in the thick of it now.
Of what?
A teenage crisis.
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello?
Yumi? It’s Franz.
I have some good news.
Tell the others and meet me
first thing tomorrow at the Factory.
Okay, we’ll be there.
I now know how to program--
--the anti-virus which will free Aelita.
All I need now is the data from Sector Five.
Great! We’ll go and get it then.
I thought the scanners
were too dangerous to use.
If we wanna to get to Sector Five,
then we have no choice.
It’ll be our final mission.
Okay, then what am I supposed to do?
If I were you,
I’d stay out of the way.
It’s not fair!
Everyone blames me for everything,
and after all we all turned on
the supercomputer back on together.
Perhaps, but you were the one
who played sorcerer’s apprentice.
You’re the one who put your
friends lives at risk.
And you’re the one who let
Xana destroy my diary.
Fine, I get it.
Jeremie!
Right, shall we?
Hello?
Dad, it’s me.
Jeremie?
You know that school for gifted children,
that you were talking about?
Yes?
I wanna go.
Can you come and get me?
When?
As soon as possible.
Okay, I’ll be there tomorrow.
Oh, right. Alright then.
Transfer Ulrich.
Transfer Yumi.
Transfer Odd.
Scanner Yumi.
Scanner Ulrich.
Scanner Odd.
Virtualization.
Hey! We’ve arrived directly in Sector Five!
Of course.
There is a direct access.
The transporter is a little outdated.
Cool!
And you’re the one who let
Xana destroy my diary…
Franz Hopper’s diary…
But how could he know,
that diary was destroyed?
Maybe you’ll find out more about
the mysterious owner of the Hermitage.
Everything’s encrypted,
I have to decode it.
And you’re the one who let
Xana destroy my diary…
Huh? How could Franz Hopper know that?!
Xana took control of you.
He destroyed all of Franz Hopper’s Cds.
Apparently had a problem with those notes.
And you’re the one who let
Xana destroy my diary…
Xana.
The countdown has begun.
Clean up, and I’ll send Aelita over.
Alright.
Franz,
I don’t mind cleaning up.
But we’re gonna need some--
--industrial strength detergent.
No problem,
I’ve programmed you some new weapons!
Uhh, I don’t see what’s new about this…
Woo-hoo! Homing darts!
There’s the key!
Leave it to me.
Ulrich, how are you doing?
It’s a done deal.
Well done Ulrich.
Olé!
It’s almost too easy.
I want more Creepers.
Don’t worry Odd.
It’s not over yet.
I’ve got more surprises in store for you.
Aelita, are you ready for virtualization?
Yes.
Shhh!
Huh?
Here we go.
Transfer Aelita.
Scanner.
Virtualization.
Yumi?
Ulrich?
Odd?
Franz, I’m not in Sector 5.
What’s going on?
Everything’s under control.
Jeremie, what are you doing here?
I just came to see
how you’re managing, Xana.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
You’re very clever Jeremie,
but you’re too late.
Hey, wanna make this a contest?
Whoever get’s the most, wins!
What’s going on? Franz?!
Something’s wrong!
Let’s get out of here.
I get the feeling we’ve been double crossed.
Bye!
Now your friends are in a little trouble.
I’ve fixed things so that they can never rematerialize.
No more life-points and it’s bye-bye!
And now, for the grand finale.
What now?
Well, there’s only one thing to do.
Franz! We need help!
No! Not Franz, Xana!
This must be the surprise…
Huh?
Hellooo? You had enough?
(DING, DING)
Ciao!
Admit you’re defeated Jeremie.
No. Not this time.
Hm?
What’s the meaning of this?!
A decoy.
Huh? Noooooo!
Wow!
I’ve often wondered how this would all end.
Now I know, this is it.
No! Ulrich!
It can’t be!
C’mon! Don’t be so pessimistic Odd.
Jeremie?
Yes, I’m back.
Come on, let’s start over.
Nothing like my trusty old gear.
What about Ulrich?
All’s well, I managed to
reprogram the materialization just in time.
He’s home.
Ready Aelita?
Yes Jeremie.
All we gotta do now,
is to deactivate the tower.
I’m sending you Aelita.
Virtualization.
Aelita, I’m entering the code SCIPIO.
Jeremie?!
What’s going on?
What can I do?
Jeremie,
I’m in the core zone.
Aelita?
Deactivate the tower, hurry up!
Hurry!
Jeremie’s in trouble.
Jeremie!
Aelita!
Hang in there, please!
(CELESTIAL HUMMING)
(HUMMING CONTINUES)
Tower deactivated.
Don’t worry buddy, everything’s okay now.
Of course I’m not angry with you.
What’s more, I checked out your bio-schematic
during your rematerialization phase.
There’s no sign of alteration whatsoever.
Oh, what a relief!
He really had me scared, that Franz Hopper.
That false Franz Hopper.
The real one is still somewhere on Lyoko.
Huh?
Dad!
Are you ready son? Let’s go.
Wait, uh, things have changed.
Lemme explain.
Huh?
You sure you’ve thought it over?
Yes.
I’m really sorry I made you come--
--all the way out here for nothing.
Don’t you worry about it.
And don’t forget to give us a call from time to time.
I promise.
Hey, what’s going on here?
Where were you going?
Nowhere.
Your father seems like a really nice guy.
Yeah, I love him.
He’s great.
Like father like son.
(LAUGHTER)
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY THE FOXTROT FANATICS